<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<book version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
      xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
      xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <info>
    <title>DocBook 中文手册</title>

    <subtitle>From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</subtitle>

    <releaseinfo>Release Version</releaseinfo>

    <author>
      <orgname>ConceptPeople consulting gmbh</orgname>
    </author>

    <pubdate>20.04.2012</pubdate>
  </info>

  <chapter>
    <title>DocBook</title>

    <section>
      <title>介绍</title>

      <para>DocBook is a semantic markup language for technical documentation.
      It was originally intended for writing technical documents related to
      computer hardware and software but it can be used for any other sort of
      documentation.As a semantic language, DocBook enables its users to
      create document content in a presentation-neutral form that captures the
      logical structure of the content; that co</para>

      <para>ntent can then be published in a variety of formats, including
      HTML, XHTML, EPUB, PDF, man pages, Web help and HTML Help, without
      requiring users to make any changes to the source.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>DocBook</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="2in" fileref="images/docbook-logo.png"></imagedata>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Overview</title>

      <para>DocBook is an XML language. In its current version (5.0),
      DocBook's language is formally defined by a RELAX NG schema with
      integrated Schematron rules. (There are also W3C XML Schema+Schematron
      and Document Type Definition (DTD) versions of the schema available, but
      these are considered non-standard.)</para>

      <para>As a semantic language, DocBook documents do not describe what
      their contents "look like," but rather the <literal>meaning</literal> of
      those contents. For example, rather than explaining how the abstract for
      an article might be visually formatted, DocBook simply says that a
      particular section <literal>is</literal> an abstract. It is up to an
      external processing tool or application to decide where on a page the
      abstract should go and what it should look like or whether or not it
      should be included in the final output at all. DocBook provides a vast
      number of semantic element tags. They are divided into three broad
      categories: structural, block-level, and inline.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Structural tags</title>

        <para>Structural tags specify broad characteristics of their contents.
        The book element, for example, specifies that its child elements
        represent the parts of a <literal>book</literal>. This includes a
        title, chapters, glossaries, appendices, and so on. DocBook's
        structural tags include, but are not limited to:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><literal>set:</literal> a titled collection of one or more
            <literal>books</literal>. Sets can be nested with other
            sets.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>book:</literal> a titled collection of
            <literal>chapters</literal>, <literal>articles</literal>, and/or
            <literal>parts</literal>, with optional glossaries, appendices,
            and so forth.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>part:</literal> a titled collection of one or more
            <literal>chapters</literal>. Parts can be nested with other parts.
            May have special introductory text.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>article:</literal> a titled, unnumbered collection
            of block-level elements.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>chapter:</literal> a titled, numbered collection of
            block-level elements. DocBook does not actually require that
            chapters be explicitly given numbers; it is understood by the
            semantics that the number of a chapter is the number of previous
            chapter elements in the XML document plus 1.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>appendix:</literal> the contained text represents
            an appendix.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>dedication:</literal> the text represents the
            dedication of the contained structural element.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Structural elements can contain other structural elements.
        Structural elements are the only permitted top-level elements in a
        DocBook document.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Block-level tags</title>

        <para>Block-level tags are elements like paragraph, lists, and so
        forth. Not all of these elements can contain actual text directly.
        Sequential block-level elements are expected to be rendered one
        "after" another. After, in this case, can differ depending on the
        language. In most Western languages, "after" means below: text
        paragraphs are printed down the page. Other languages' writing systems
        can have different directionality; for example, in Japanese, text is
        often printed in columns, with paragraphs running from right to left,
        so "after" in that case would be to the left. DocBook semantics are
        entirely neutral to these kinds of language-based concepts.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Inline-level tags</title>

        <para>Inline-level tags are elements like emphasis, hyperlinks, and so
        forth. They wrap text within a block-level element. These elements do
        not cause the text to break when rendered in a paragraph format, but
        typically they cause the document processor to apply some kind of
        distinct typographical treatment to the enclosed text, by changing the
        font, size, or similar attributes. (The DocBook specification does say
        that it expects different typographical treatment, but it does not
        offer specific requirements as to what this treatment may be.) That
        is, it is not required that a DocBook processor transform an
        <literal>emphasis</literal> tag into "italics." A reader-based DocBook
        processor could increase the volume of the words. Or, a text-based
        processor could use bold instead of italics.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Sample document</title>

      <example>
          <title>Simple Book Sample</title>

          <programlisting language="xml">&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?&gt;
&lt;book xml:id="simple_book" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0"&gt;
  &lt;title&gt;Very simple book&lt;/title&gt;
  &lt;chapter xml:id="chapter_1"&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;para&gt;Hello world!&lt;/para&gt;
    &lt;para&gt;I hope that your day is proceeding 
    &lt;emphasis&gt;splendidly&lt;/emphasis&gt;!&lt;/para&gt;
  &lt;/chapter&gt;
  &lt;chapter xml:id="chapter_2"&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;para&gt;Hello again, world!&lt;/para&gt;
  &lt;/chapter&gt;
&lt;/book&gt;</programlisting>
        </example>

      <para>Semantically, this document is a "book," with a "title," that
      contains two "chapters" each with their own "titles." Those "chapters"
      contain "paragraphs" that have text in them. The markup is fairly
      readable in English. In more detail, the root element of the document is
      book. All DocBook elements are in an XML Namespace, so the root element
      has an <emphasis>xmlns</emphasis> attribute to set the current
      namespace. Also, the root element of a DocBook document must have a
      <emphasis>version</emphasis> that specifies the version of the format
      that the document is built on. (XML documents can include elements from
      multiple namespaces at once. For simplicity, the example does not
      illustrate this.)</para>

      <para>A <literal>book</literal> element must contain a
      <literal>title</literal>, or an <literal>info</literal> element
      containing a <literal>title</literal>. This must be before any child
      structural elements. Following the title are the structural children, in
      this case, two <literal>chapter</literal> elements. Each of these must
      have a <literal>title</literal>. They contain <literal>para</literal>
      block elements which can contain free text and other inline elements
      like the <literal>emphasis</literal> in the second paragraph of the
      first chapter.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Schemas and validation</title>

      <para>Rules such as the ones alluded to in the preceding paragraph
      (<emphasis>"a book element must contain a title, or an info element
      containing a title,"</emphasis> etc.) are formally defined in the
      DocBook <emphasis>schema</emphasis>. Appropriate programming tools can
      be used to <emphasis>validate</emphasis> an XML document (DocBook or
      otherwise), against its corresponding schema, in order to determine if
      (and if so, where) the document fails to conform to that schema. XML
      editing tools can also use schema information to avoid creating
      non-conforming documents in the first place.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>DocBook authoring</title>

      <para>Because DocBook is XML, documents can be created and edited with
      any text editor. A dedicated XML Editor is likewise a functional DocBook
      editor. DocBook provides schema files for popular XML schema languages,
      so any XML Editor that can provide content completion based on a schema
      can do so for DocBook. Many graphical or WYSIWYG XML editors come with
      the ability to edit DocBook like a Word Processor.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>DocBook processing</title>

      <para>Because DocBook is an XML format, conforming to a well-defined
      schema, documents can be validated and processed using any tool or
      programming language which includes XML support. DocBook files are used
      to prepare output files in a wide variety of formats. Nearly always,
      this is accomplished using DocBook XSL stylesheets. These are XSLT
      stylesheets that transform DocBook documents into a number of formats
      (HTML, XSL-FO for later conversion into PDF, etc.). These stylesheets
      can be sophisticated enough to generate tables of contents, glossaries,
      and indexes. They can oversee the selection of particular designated
      portions of a master document to produce different versions of the same
      document (such as a "tutorial" or a "quick-reference guide," where both
      of these consist of a subset of the material). Because the standard
      DocBook XSL stylesheets <emphasis>are</emphasis> well-formed XSL
      stylesheets, and DocBook <emphasis>is</emphasis> well-formed XML, users
      can write their own customized stylesheets or even a full-fledged
      program to process the DocBook into an appropriate output format as
      their needs dictate.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>History</title>

      <para>DocBook began in 1991 in discussion groups on Usenet and evenually
      became a joint project of HAL Computer Systems and O'Reilly &amp;
      Associates and eventually spawned its own maintenance organization (the
      Davenport Group) before moving in 1998 to the SGML Open consortium,
      which subsequently became OASIS. DocBook is currently maintained by the
      DocBook Technical Committee at OASIS. DocBook is available in both SGML
      and XML forms, as a DTD. RELAX NG and W3C XML Schema forms of the XML
      version are available. Starting with DocBook 5, the RELAX NG version is
      the "normative" form from which the other formats are generated. DocBook
      originally started out as an SGML application, but an equivalent XML
      application was developed and has now replaced the SGML one for most
      uses. (Starting with version 4 of the SGML DTD, the XML DTD continued
      with this version numbering scheme.) Initially, a key group of software
      companies used DocBook since their representatives were involved in its
      initial design. Eventually, however, DocBook was adopted by the open
      source community where it has become a standard for creating
      documentation for many projects, including FreeBSD, KDE, GNOME desktop
      documentation, the GTK+ API references, the Linux kernel documentation,
      and the work of the Linux Documentation Project. Norman Walsh and the
      DocBook Project development team maintain the key application for
      producing output from DocBook source documents: A set of XSL stylesheets
      (as well as a legacy set of DSSSL stylesheets) that can generate
      high-quality HTML and print (FO/PDF) output, as well as output in other
      formats, including RTF, man pages and HTML Help. Walsh is also the
      principal author of the book <citation>DocBook 5: The Definitive Guide 2012</citation>,
      the official documentation of DocBook. This book is
      available online under the GFDL, and also as a print publication.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Apache Maven</title>

    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>

      <para>Maven is a build automation tool typically used for Java projects.
      Maven serves a similar purpose to the Apache Ant tool, but it is based
      on different concepts and works in a profoundly different manner. It can
      also be used to build and manage projects written in C#, Ruby, Scala,
      and other languages. Maven is hosted by the Apache Software Foundation,
      where it was formerly part of the Jakarta Project.</para>

      <para>Maven uses an XML file to describe the software project being
      built, its dependencies on other external modules and components, the
      build order, directories, and required plug-ins. It comes with
      pre-defined targets for performing certain well-defined tasks such as
      compilation of code and its packaging.</para>

      <para>Maven dynamically downloads Java libraries and Maven plug-ins from
      one or more repositories such as the Maven 2 Central Repository. This
      local cache of downloaded artifacts can also be updated with artifacts
      created by local projects. Public repositories can also be
      updated.</para>

      <para>Maven is built using a plugin-based architecture that allows it to
      make use of any application controllable through standard input.
      Theoretically, this would allow anyone to write plugins to interface
      with build tools (compilers, unit test tools, etc.) for any other
      language. In reality, support and use for languages other than Java has
      been minimal. Currently a plugin for the .NET framework exists and is
      maintained, and a C/C++ native plugin is maintained for Maven 2
      maven-native and maven-nar.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Apache Maven</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata contentwidth="2in" fileref="images/maven_logo.gif"></imagedata>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Example</title>

      <para>Maven projects are configured using a Project Object Model, which
      is stored in a <filename>pom.xml</filename>-file. Here's a minimal
      example:</para>

      <example>
          <title>Maven Example</title>

          <programlisting language="xml">&lt;project&gt;
  &lt;!-- model version is always 4.0.0 for Maven 2.x POMs --&gt;
  &lt;modelVersion&gt;4.0.0&lt;/modelVersion&gt;
 
  &lt;!-- project coordinates, i.e. a group of values which
       uniquely identify this project --&gt;
  &lt;groupId&gt;com.mycompany.app&lt;/groupId&gt;
  &lt;artifactId&gt;my-app&lt;/artifactId&gt;
  &lt;version&gt;1.0&lt;/version&gt;
 
  &lt;!-- library dependencies --&gt;
  &lt;dependencies&gt;
    &lt;dependency&gt;
 
      &lt;!-- coordinates of the required library --&gt;
      &lt;groupId&gt;junit&lt;/groupId&gt;
      &lt;artifactId&gt;junit&lt;/artifactId&gt;
      &lt;version&gt;3.8.1&lt;/version&gt;
 
      &lt;!--this dependency is only used for running and compiling tests--&gt;
      &lt;scope&gt;test&lt;/scope&gt;
 
    &lt;/dependency&gt;
  &lt;/dependencies&gt;
&lt;/project&gt;</programlisting>
        </example>

      <para>This POM only defines a unique identifier for the project
      (<emphasis>coordinates</emphasis>) and its dependency on the JUnit
      framework. However, that is already enough for building the project and
      running the unit tests associated with the project. Maven accomplishes
      this by embracing the idea of Convention over Configuration, that is,
      Maven provides default values for the project's configuration. The
      directory structure of a normal idiomatic Maven project has the
      following directory entries:</para>

      <informaltable>
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <colspec colwidth="*" />

          <colspec colwidth="*" />

          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>Directory name</entry>

              <entry>Purpose</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>project home</entry>

              <entry>Contains the pom.xml and all subdirectories.</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>src/main/java</entry>

              <entry>Contains the deliverable Java sourcecode for the
              project.</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>src/main/resources</entry>

              <entry>Contains the deliverable resources for the project, such
              as property files.</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>src/test/java</entry>

              <entry>Contains the testing classes (JUnit or TestNG test cases,
              for example) for the project.</entry>
            </row>

            <row>
              <entry>src/test/resources</entry>

              <entry>Contains resources necessary for testing.</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </informaltable>

      <para>Then the command</para>

      <programlisting>mvn package</programlisting>

      <para>will compile all the Java files, run any tests, and package the
      deliverable code and resources into
      <filename>target/my-app-1.0.jar</filename> (assuming the artifactId is
      my-app and the version is 1.0.) Using Maven itself, the user provides
      only configuration for the project, while the configurable plug-ins do
      the actual work of compiling the project, cleaning target directories,
      running unit tests, generating API documentation and so on. In general,
      users should not have to write plugins themselves. Contrast this with
      Ant and make in which one writes imperative procedures for doing the
      aforementioned tasks.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Concepts</title>

      <section>
        <title>Project Object Model</title>

        <para>A Project Object Model (POM) provides all the configuration for
        a single project. General configuration covers the project's name, its
        owner and its dependencies on other projects. One can also configure
        individual phases of the build process, which are implemented as
        plugins. For example, one can configure the compiler-plugin to use
        Java version 1.5 for compilation, or specify packaging the project
        even if some unit test fails. Larger projects should be divided into
        several modules, or sub-projects, each with its own POM. One can then
        write a root POM through which one can compile all the modules with a
        single command. POMs can also inherit configuration from other POMs.
        All POMs inherit from the Super POM by default. The Super POM provides
        default configuration, such as default source directories, default
        plugins, and so on.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Plugins</title>

        <para>Most of Maven's functionality is in plugins. A plugin provides a
        set of goals that can be executed using the following syntax:</para>

        <programlisting>mvn [plugin-name]:[goal-name]</programlisting>

        <para>For example, a Java project can be compiled with the
        compiler-plugin's compile-goal by running mvn
        <literal>compiler:compile</literal>. There are Maven plugins for
        building, testing, source control management, running a web server,
        generating Eclipse project files, and much more. Plugins are
        introduced and configured in a &lt;plugins&gt;-section of a
        <filename>pom.xml</filename> file. Some basic plugins are included in
        every project by default, and they have sensible default
        settings.</para>

        <para>However, it would be cumbersome if one would have to run several
        goals manually in order to build, test and package a project:</para>

        <programlisting> mvn compiler:compile
 mvn surefire:test
 mvn jar:jar</programlisting>

        <para>Maven's lifecycle-concept handles this issue.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Build lifecycles</title>

        <para>Build lifecycle is a list of named <emphasis>phases</emphasis>
        that can be used to give order to goal execution. One of Maven's
        standard lifecycles is the <emphasis>default lifecycle</emphasis>,
        which includes the following phases, in this order:<footnote>
            <para><link
            xlink:href="http://maven.apache.org/guides/introduction/introduction-to-the-lifecycle.html#Lifecycle_Reference">http://maven.apache.org/guides/introduction/introduction-to-the-lifecycle.html#Lifecycle_Reference</link></para>
          </footnote></para>

        <orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><literal>process-resources</literal></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>compile</literal></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>process-test-resources</literal></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>test-compile</literal></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>test</literal></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>package</literal></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>install</literal></para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para><literal>deploy</literal></para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>

        <para>Goals provided by plugins can be associated with different
        phases of the lifecycle. For example, by default, the goal
        "compiler:compile" is associated with the compile-phase, while the
        goal "surefire:test" is associated with the test-phase. When the
        command</para>

        <programlisting>mvn test</programlisting>

        <para>is executed, Maven will run all the goals associated with each
        of the phases up to the test-phase. So it will run the
        "resources:resources"-goal associated with the
        process-resources-phase, then "compiler:compile", and so on until it
        finally runs the "surefire:test"-goal. Maven also has standard
        lifecycles for cleaning the project and for generating a project site.
        If cleaning were part of the default lifecycle, the project would be
        cleaned every time it was built. This is clearly undesirable, so
        cleaning has been given its own lifecycle. Thanks to standard
        lifecycles, one should be able to build, test and install every
        Maven-project using the <literal>mvn install</literal>-command.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Dependencies</title>

        <para>The example section hinted at Maven's dependency-handling
        mechanism. A project that needs the Hibernate-library simply has to
        declare Hibernate's project coordinates in its POM. Maven will
        automatically download the dependency and the dependencies that
        Hibernate itself needs (called transitive dependencies) and store them
        in the user's local repository. Maven 2 Central Repository is used by
        default to search for libraries, but one can configure the
        repositories used (e.g. company-private repositories) in POM. There
        are search engines such as Maven Central, which can be used to find
        out coordinates for different open-source libraries and frameworks.
        Projects developed on a single machine can depend on each other
        through the local repository. The local repository is a simple folder
        structure which acts both as a cache for downloaded dependencies and
        as a centralized storage place for locally built artifacts. The Maven
        command <literal>mvn install</literal> builds a project and places its
        binaries in the local repository. Then other projects can utilize this
        project by specifying its coordinates in their POMs.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Comparison with similar tools</title>

      <para>The fundamental difference between Maven and Ant is that Maven's
      design regards all projects as having a certain structure and a set of
      supported task work-flows (e.g. getting resources from source control,
      compiling the project, unit testing, etc.). While most software projects
      in effect support these operations and actually do have a well-defined
      structure, Maven requires that this structure and the operation
      implementation details be defined in the POM file. Thus, Maven relies on
      a convention on how to define projects and on the list of work-flows
      that are generally supported in all projects.</para>

      <para>This design constraint is more like how an IDE handles projects
      and it provides many benefits, such as a succinct project definition and
      the possibility of automatic integration of a Maven project with other
      development tools such as IDEs, build servers, etc. The downside is that
      it requires a user to first understand what a project is from the Maven
      point of view and how Maven works with projects, because what happens
      when one executes a phase in Maven is not immediately obvious just from
      examining the Maven project file. This required structure is also often
      a barrier in migrating a mature project to Maven because it is usually
      hard to adapt from other approaches.</para>

      <para>In Ant, projects do not really exist from the tool's technical
      perspective. Ant works with XML build scripts defined in one or more
      files. It processes targets from these files and each target executes
      tasks. Each task performs a technical operation such as running a
      compiler or copying files around. Tasks are executed primarily in the
      order given by their defined dependency on other tasks. Thus, Ant is a
      tool that chains together tasks and executes them based on
      inter-dependencies and other Boolean conditions.</para>

      <para>The benefits provided by Ant are also numerous. It has an XML
      language optimized for clearer definition of what each task does and on
      what it depends. Also, all the information about what will be executed
      by an Ant target can be found in the Ant script. A developer not
      familiar with Ant would normally be able to determine what a simple Ant
      script does just by examining the script. This is not usually true for
      Maven.</para>

      <para>However, even an experienced developer that is new to a project
      using Ant cannot infer what the higher level structure of an Ant script
      is and what it does without examining the script in detail. Depending on
      the script's complexity, this can quickly become a daunting challenge.
      With Maven, a developer who previously worked with other Maven projects
      can quickly examine the structure of a never before seen Maven project
      and execute the standard Maven work-flows against it while already
      knowing what to expect as an outcome.</para>

      <para>It is possible to use Ant scripts that are defined and behave in a
      uniform manner for all projects in a working group or an organization.
      However, when the number and complexity of projects rises, it is also
      very easy to stray from the initially desired uniformity. With Maven
      this is less of a problem because the tool always imposes a certain way
      of doing things.</para>

      <para>Note that it is also possible to extend and configure Maven in a
      way that departs from the Maven way of doing things.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>IDE integration</title>

      <para>Add-ons to several popular Integrated Development Environments
      exist to provide integration of Maven with the IDE's build mechanism and
      source editing tools, allowing Maven to compile projects from within the
      IDE, and also to set the classpath for code completion, highlighting
      compiler errors, etc. Examples of popular IDEs supporting development
      with Maven include:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><link
          xlink:href="http://www.eclipse.org/">Eclipse</link></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><link xlink:href="http://netbeans.org/">NetBeans</link></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><link xlink:href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/">IntelliJ
          IDEA</link></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><link
          xlink:href="http://www.embarcadero.com/products/jbuilder">JBuilder</link></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><link
          xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/developer-tools/jdev/overview/index.html">JDeveloper</link></para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><link
          xlink:href="http://www.myeclipseide.com/">MyEclipse</link></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>These add-ons also provide the ability to edit the POM or use the
      POM to determine a project's complete set of dependencies directly
      within the IDE.</para>

      <para>Some built-in features of IDEs are forfeited when the IDE no
      longer performs compilation. For example, Eclipse's JDT has the ability
      to recompile a single java source file after it has been edited. Many
      IDEs work with a flat set of projects instead of the hierarchy of
      folders preferred by Maven. This complicates the use of SCM systems in
      IDEs when using Maven.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>History</title>

      <para>Maven, created by Sonatype's Jason van Zyl, began as a subproject
      of Apache Turbine in 2002. In 2003, it was voted on and accepted as a
      top level Apache Software Foundation project. In July 2004, Maven was
      released as the critical first milestone, v1.0. Maven 2 was declared
      v2.0 in October 2005 after about 6 months in beta cycles. Maven 3.0 was
      released in October 2010 being mostly backwards compatible with Maven
      2.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Future</title>

      <para>Maven 3.0 information began trickling out in 2008. After eight
      alpha releases, the first beta version of Maven 3.0 was released in
      April 2010. Maven 3.0 has reworked the core Project Builder
      infrastructure such that the POMs file-based representation is now
      decoupled from its in-memory object representation. This has expanded
      the possibility for Maven 3.0 add-ons to leverage non-XML based project
      definition files. Languages suggested include Ruby (already in private
      prototype by Jason van Zyl), YAML, and Groovy. Experimental work for a
      YAML-based POM definition file (requires an external conversion script
      to be executed) has been piloted by Don Brown of Atlassian. Special
      attention has been paid to ensuring compatibility between Maven 2 and 3.
      For most projects, an upgrade to Maven 3 won't require any adjustments
      of their project structure. The first beta of Maven 3 saw the
      introduction of a parallel build feature which leverages a configurable
      number of cores on a multi-core machine and is especially suited for
      large multi-module projects.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <bibliography>
    <title>Referenzen</title>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>DocBook Wikipedia 2012</abbrev><title>Wikipedia Artikel zu
    DocBook http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DocBook</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>Apache Maven Wikipedia 2012</abbrev><title>Wikipedia
    Artikel zu Apache Maven
    http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apache_maven</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>DocBook 5: The Definitive Guide 2012</abbrev>
    <title>HTML-Version (1.0.1) des Buchs von Norman Walsh
    http://www.docbook.org/tdg5/</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>DocBook XSL: The Complete Guide 2007</abbrev>
    <title>DocBook 5 Guide von Bob Stayton
    http://www.sagehill.net/docbookxsl/index.html</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>DocBook XSL Stylesheets: Reference Documentation</abbrev>
    <title>Parameter Reference von Norman Walsh
    http://docbook.xml-doc.org/snapshots/xsl/doc/index.html</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>Docbkx-Tool 2012</abbrev><title>DocBook Maven Plugin
    http://docbkx-tools.sourceforge.net/</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>Docbkx User Guide 2012</abbrev>
    <title>Beispielkonfigurationen für das Maven Docbkx Plugin
    http://docbkx-tools.sourceforge.net/docbkx-samples/manual.html</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>FOP Pdf-Images 2010</abbrev>
    <title>Erweiterung für Apache FOP um PDF-Images
    http://www.jeremias-maerki.ch/download/fop/pdf-images/
    </title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>POM Reference 2012</abbrev><title>Konfiguration einer
    Maven pom-Datei http://maven.apache.org/pom.html</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>Processing XML with Java 2002</abbrev>
    <title>Beschreibung von Elliotte Rusty Harold wie man XSLT um Java erweitert
    http://cafeconleche.org/books/xmljava/chapters/ch17s03.html</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>EXSLT 2006</abbrev><title>Erweiterung von XSLT um
    neue Funktionen http://www.exslt.org/</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>XML Bible 2001</abbrev><title>Fünf Beispielkapitel
    aus der XML Bibel von Elliotte Rusty Harold
    http://www.cafeconleche.org/books/bible2/chapters/</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>DocBook FAQ</abbrev><title>Häufig gestellte Fragen zu
    DocBook http://www.dpawson.co.uk/docbook/</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>XSL FAQ</abbrev><title>Häufig gestellte Fragen zu XSL
    http://www.dpawson.co.uk/xsl/index.html</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>Maven Docbook for beginners 2010</abbrev><title>Quick
    Start für Docbook mit Maven
    http://www.vineetmanohar.com/2010/02/maven-docbook-for-beginners/</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>XMLmind XML Editor 2012</abbrev><title>Editor für
    Docbook-Dokumente http://www.xmlmind.com/xmleditor/</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>XSL-FO Tutorial 2012</abbrev><title>XSL-FO Tutorial
    mit Anwendungsbeispielen
    http://www.data2type.de/xml-xslt-xslfo/xsl-fo</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>XSL-FO Tutorial 2007</abbrev><title>XSL-FO Tutorial
    als PDF
    http://www.ecrion.com/Support/PDF/XSL-FOTutorial.pdf</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>DocBook Wiki 2012</abbrev><title>Wiki von NormanWalsh
    über DocBook http://wiki.docbook.org/Home</title></bibliomixed>

    <bibliomixed><abbrev>Using DocBook XSL Stylesheets 2003</abbrev>
    <title>Anleitung für DocBook XSL Stylesheets von Robert Stayton
    http://xml.web.cern.ch/XML/www.sagehill.net/xml/docbookxsl/index.html</title></bibliomixed>
  </bibliography>
</book>
